Guide to the Elisabeth Lloyd Papers, 1954-2017 ASP.2016.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Composition - Working Notes, 1978 - 2014; III.
  - Writing Process, 1982 - 2014; 4.
    - Melinda's Comments on Sarkar (1994), 2004 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Melinda on Genic Selection Manuscript, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Genic Selection Notes, July 2004 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Genic Selection Outline, July 2004 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Genic Selection Notes from Feldman Meetings, 2004-2006 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Rumors About Selection Outline of Points, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Rumors About Selection - Elisabeth Lloyd, Richard Lewontin, and Marc Feldman (LLF), 2005 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Rumors About Selection Working Drafts Feldman Changes, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Talk with Pat Suppes, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Female Orgasm Survey, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Lloyd, Lewontin, and Feldman Research Notes, February 2006 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Lloyd, Lewontin, and Feldman Notes from Lewontin Meetings, March 2006 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Lloyd, Lewontin, and Feldman Notes, June 2006 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Lloyd, Lewontin, and Feldman Outline, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Lloyd, Lewontin, and Feldman - BSRG - Notes/Diagrams, May 2006 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Melinda Meeting, July 2006 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Jim Woodward's Comments on Lloyd's Robustness and Variety of Evidence: A Case of Climate Models, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Encyclopedia of Life Sciences agreement between Lloyd and Sean Valles, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - APA Comments for Climate Change Session - Kevin Elliott's Comments on Lloyd's Paper, 2012 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Notes for Sex Differences in Partnered Orgasm Experience Among U.S. Singles, 2012-2013 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Model Robustness Final Philosophy of Science Reviews, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - New Questions for Sex Survey, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Objectivity and a Comparison of Methodological Scenario Approaches for Climate Change Research, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Reviewer Comments on Manuscript for Synthese on Objectivity, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Sex Differences in Partnered Orgasm Experience Across Age, Sexual Orientation, and Relationship Status, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Model Robustness as a Confirmatory Virtue: Variety of Evidence and Climate Science, 2014 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Reviewer Comments on Model Robustness as a Confirmatory Virtue, 2014 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - A Semantic Approach to the Structure of Population Genetics Notes and Chapter 3 Conclusion (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Altruism and Genic Selection (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 3 Inserts for an Unknown Publication (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Commitment Sheets for Keywords in Evolutionary Biology (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Confirmation Notes (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Constructing and Confirming Models in Population Biology (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Darwin History Paper Notes (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Darwin Paper Notes (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Darwin's Support for his Theory of Natural Selection (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - D.J. Hosken Criticism of Wallen and Lloyd and Wallen and Lloyd's Response, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Evolutionary Algorithms and Social Exchange: A Critique of Evolutionary Psychology Elisabeth Lloyd and Marcus Feldman (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Fitness Components (Quantitative) (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Freq. Dep. and Measures of Genotype Fitness (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Genic Selection (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Genic Selection Paper Comments from Tim Lewen (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Genic Selectionism Paper Comment Request Form (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Group Selection Notes (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Idea for Paper on Adaptationism (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Keywords in Evolutionary Biology Suggestion Letters (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Method of Weights (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous Notecards (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Notes for Chapter 1 of an Unknown Publication (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Notes on Lloyd, Lewontin, and Feldman (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Research Citations (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Model Robustness Submission to Philosophy of Science with Reviewer Comments (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Model Robustness Submission to Studies in History and Philosophy of Science and Reviewer Comments (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Montreal paper - Selection Models and the Darwinian Theory of Natural Selection (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Optim Model Notes (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Orgasm Questionnaire (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - POS Submissions - Genic Selection Paper Reports 1 and 2 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Problems with Optimality Models (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Response to Referees - Robustness for Philosophy of Science Outline (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Revisions to Synthese Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Rumors About Selection Introduction with Handwritten Notes (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Rumors About Selection Introduction - Elisabeth Lloyd, Richard Lewontin, and Marc Feldman (LLF) (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Selection Models and the Darwinian Theory of Natural Selection (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Sociobiology and Sex Roles (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Speciation models notes for paper (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Species Selection drafts and notes - E.A. Lloyd and Stephen Jay Gould (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - State Space Ecology and Genetics (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - The Case of the Female Orgasm FAQs (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - The Case of the Female Orgasm Order Form (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Units and Levels of Selection: An Anatomy of the Units of Selection Debates (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Units and Levels of Selection notes (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - 5.3 Kin Selection and Genic Selection (Box 24, Folder 24)
- Teaching Materials, 1986 - 2013; IV.
  These are materials used by Professor Lloyd in teaching classes, chiefly undergraduate classes in Philosophpy, at various institutions including the University of California, Berkeley and the University of Indiana, Bloominton. The materials in this section are arranged chronologically. Whenever possible materials are arranged by number and aname. The supplemental materials include course evaluations, lecture planning notes, slides, overhead projector panels, and letters of recommendation. The letters of recommendation are sequestered for 75 years.
  - Classes, 1988 - 2016; 1.
    - Term Course Lists - Harvard University, Spring 1998 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - History and Philosophy of Science X320: Issues in Biology and Medicine - Indiana University, Fall 1999 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Evolution, Religion, and Society - Indiana University, Spring 1999 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - X320 Human Nature: Theories and Implications - Indiana University, 2004-2005 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Schedule of Courses - Indiana University, Fall 2009 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - History and Philosophy of Science 451/551 Philosophy of Science - Indiana University (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Philosophy 129 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Fall 1988 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Philosophy 5 - UC Berkeley, Spring 1990 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Philosophy 290 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Spring 1990 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Philosophy 290-3 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Fall 1991 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Philosophy 5: Science and Human Understanding - UC Berkeley, Fall 1992 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Philosophy 5 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Fall 1992 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Philosophy 129 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Fall 1992 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Philosophy 185 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Srping 1993 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Philosophy 290.3 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Spring 1993 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Philosophy 290-2 Objectivity Graduate Seminar- UC Berkeley, Fall 1993 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Philosophy 129 - UC Berkeley, Srping 1994 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Philosophy 129 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Spring 1994 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Philosophy 128: Philosophy of Science Make-Up Final Exam - UC Berkeley, Fall 1994 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Philosophy 290 Theories of Explanation and American Pragmatism- UC Berkeley, Fall 1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Philosophy 290 Section 6 Course Reader - UC Berkeley, Fall 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Freshman Seminar Program Evaluations - UC Berkeley, Fall 1994 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Philosophy 5 Science and Human Understanding - UC Berkeley, Spring 1995 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Philosophy 39: Freshman Seminar: Human Nature - UC Berkeley, Spring 1996 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Philosophy 5 - UC Berkeley, Fall 1996 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Philosophy 290-4 Inductive Inference and Rationality - UC Berkeley, Spring 1996 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - History and Philosophy of Science X100 Course Reader - Indiana University, Spring 1997 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Philosophy 129 - UC Berkeley, Spring 1997 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Philosophy 290-3: Scientific Explanation First Paper Assignment - UC Berkeley, Fall 1997 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Philosophy 149 Philosophy of Science - Indiana University, Spring 1998 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - History and Philosophy of Science X100 Course Reader - Indiana University, Fall 1998 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - X755 American Pragmatism Course Readers - Indiana University, Fall 1999 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - X320: Issues in Biology and Medicine - Indiana University, Fall 1999 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - HPS 756 Philosophy of Biology Graduate Seminar, Spring 2000 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - History and Philosophy X706 Course Reader Vol. 1 - Indiana University, Spring 2001 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - History and Philosophy X706 Course Reader Vol. 2 - Indiana University, Spring 2001 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - History and Philosophy X706 Course Reader Vol. 3 - Indiana University, Spring 2001 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - X755 Course Reader - Indiana University, Fall 2002 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - X551: Philosophy of Science, Fall 2013 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - X305, Spring 2016 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - X755: Models in Science and Philosophy of Science, Fall 2016 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Philsophy 518a: The Works - Graduate class (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Supplemental Material, 1986 - 2013; 2.
    - Course Evaluations - Indiana University, 1999-2013 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Book Orders, 1993-1994 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Books to Order (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Interactions with Students, 1986-2006 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Lecture Planning (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Links for Class Units (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - BIOS 431, March 2001 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Overhead Projector Slides (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Reading Assignments (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Sociobiology Lecture (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Topics for Class, 1997-2003 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - CS104 S12 Lecture Quizzes (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - HPSC Faculty Meetings (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Philosophy 5 notes - Toxins, Risk Assessment, Risk Management (Box 29, Folder 14)
- Talks to Professional Groups, 1990 - 2017; V.
  This section contains material documenting talks that Lloyd gave to professional organizations and at other universities. These were given on topics in philosophy and biology.
  - Talks at Various Educational Institutions, 1984 - 2016; 1.
    - Amsterdam talk - Public, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - The Confirmation of the Scientific Theories University of California San Diego, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - C.U. Boulder Talk, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Cognitive Science Talk - UCSD, 1986-1987 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Approaches to Testing and Confirmation, Florence, Italy, March 1988 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Defense of Feminist Empiricism, University of California at Davis, Spring 1988 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Evolution and Cogniton, UC Davis, April 1990 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Talk About Dennett, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Locker Room Science: Social and Theoretical Influences on Evolutionary Explanations of Women's Sexuality, Center for the Critical Analysis of Contemporary Culture, Rutgers University, November 1991 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Reductionism in Biology Today University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill Colloquium Talk, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Objectivity and Pragmatism, Center for Philosophy of Science 25th Annual Lecture Series, University of Pittsburgh, December 1994 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Talk on Cosmides (1989), Northwestern University, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Santa Barbara Talk, 2011 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - The Logic of Research Questions: Adaptationism in Action in the Case of the Female Orgasm, Inaugural Lecture POBAM, University of Wisconsin, Madison, May 2012 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Climate Models: How Should We Understand Their Robustness? SUNY Stony Brook, May 2013 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - 'Model Robustness' as a Confirmatory Virtue: 'The Case of Climate Models' Groningen, The Netherlands University, May 2014 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - What is Wrong with the Way that Many Animal Behaviorists and Anthropologists ("Adaptationists") Research Evolutionary Traits? Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, February 2016 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Amsterdam talk - Interrelations (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Confirmation of Scientific Theories - notes - University of Colorado Boulder (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Confirmation Paper - University of San Diego (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Model Robustness in Climate Science Washington University (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Overhead Slides for Female Orgasm Talk (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Penn Talk Notes (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - SUNY Model Robustness Talk (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - University of California San Diego talk (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Talks to Professional Organizations, 1988 - 2017; 2.
    - Gender as a Methodological Category talk for SSSS, Amsterdam, November 1988 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - The Kinsey Institute Interdisciplinary Seminar Series, Spring 1999 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Problems with Pluralism, Oslo, Norway, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Aristotelian Society Talk Notes, 2009 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - In Memory of David Hull, ISH, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Gould and Adaptation: San Marco 33 Years Later, Stephen J. Gould's Legacy: Nature, History, Society Conference, Venice, May 2012 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Dewey Lecture, 2013 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Thinking About Being Robust: Causes, Convergence, and Climate Models IDAG Talk: International Ad Hoc Detection and Attribution Group, June 2013 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - The Evolution of the Female Orgasm Aspasia Lecture, Groningen, May 2014 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Slowing Down and Enjoying Sex: On Why Nature Built Women to Have Difficulty Coming with Intercourse Brooklyn Public Library, January 2017 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Wells Club Presentation, February 2017 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Structure and Confirmation of Evolutionary Theory (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Library, 1954 - 2014; VI.
  The library contains annotated books, preprints, reprints, and other professional literature with annotations. There are also Ph.D. dissertations of Lloyd's students; which are not annotated.
  - Annotated Reprints, 1980 - 2012; 1.
    - Abir-Am, Pnina G., 1996 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Balzer, W. and Dawe, C.M., 1986 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Boynton, Robert S. From Dick, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Braaten, Jane, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Brison, Susan, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Browne, Kingsley, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Caporael, Linnda, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Collier, John D., 1992 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Collwell, Robert K. and King, Mary-Claire, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Conkey, Margaret, 1990-2000 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Creath, Richard, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Dugatkin, Lee Alan, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Dupré, John, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Eichel, Edward, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Fausto-Sterling, Anne, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Finkel, Steve E., 2000 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Fricker, Janet, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Gale, Richard M., 1991 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Grene, Marjorie, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Griesemer, James, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Haack, Susan, 1995-1997 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Haraway, Donna, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Hartman, Hyman, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Kirkpatrick, R.C. from Rebecca Finnell, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Kittay, Jeffrey, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Kreiling, Ken, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Latour, Bruno, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Lewontin, Richard sent by Rachel, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Lloyd, James B., 1993 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Martin, Wayne M., 1992 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Mayr, Ernst, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - McGuire, Michael, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Meli, Domenico Bertoloni, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Mertz, Dick, 1997-1998 (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Newman, Stuart, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - Ramsey, Grant, 2007 (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - Rehmann-Sutter, Christoph, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Richardson, Alan, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - Sal, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - Sattler, Rolf, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Schloegel, Judy, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Schwitzgebel, Eric, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Simpson, Lorenzo, 2012 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Skyrms, Brian, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Sober, Elliott, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Staley, Kent W., 1999 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Strathern, Marilyn, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Taylor, Peter, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Wake, David and Larson, Allan from Renee, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Winther, Rasmus, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Witts, Juliet, 1999-2000 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Wolpert, Lewis, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Wylie, Alison, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Annotated Articles, 1970 - 2014; 2.
    - Allen, Garland, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Applying Multilevel Selection Theory to Analyses of Neighborhood Decline in US Cities - Lloyd's Comments (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Arnold, Anthony J. et al., 1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Brandom, Bob (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Burian, Richard M., 1983 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Douglas, Heather, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Ewens, Warren J., 2014 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Fox, C.A. et al., 1970 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Grafen, Alan, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Griesemer, James, 2011 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Kelly, Shona et al., 1997 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Kerr, Benjamin and Peter Godfrey-Smith, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Knutti, Reto, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Ladyman, James, 2000 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Love, Alan C., 2012 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Mann, Mike (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Marx, Karl and Engels, Frederick (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Mearns, Linda O. et al., 2014 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Otsuka, Jun (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Pievani, Telmo, 2011 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Puts, David A. (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Soloman, Miriam, 2013 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Stone, Linda et al., 2005 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Unknown Author, Gould Talking Past Dawkins on the Unit of Selection Issue (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - van Fraassen, Bas (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Walsh, Denis M., 2010-2013 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Winther, Rasmus et al., 2013 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Annotated Books, 1954 - 1996; 3.
    - Burtt, E.A., 1954 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Kitcher, Philip, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Published Articles, 1983 - 2015; 4.
    - The Nature of Darwin's Support for the Theory of Natural Selection, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - A Semantic Approach to the Structure of Population Genetics and Proof, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - 'Intelligent' Evolution and Neo-Darwinian Straw Men, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Species Selection on Variability Elisabeth Lloyd and Stephen Jay Gould, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Empiricism, Objectivity, and Explanation - Elisabeth Lloyd and Carl Anderson, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Pre-Theoretical Assumptions in Evolutionary Explanations of Female Sexuality, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Normality and Variation: The Human Genome Project and the Ideal Human Type, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Rx: Distinguish Group Selection from Group Adaptation, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Objectivity and the Double Standard for Feminist Epistemologies, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Feminism As Method: What Scientists Get That Philosophers Don't, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - The Anachronistic Anarchist, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Science and Anti-Science: Objectivity and its Real Enemies, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Altruism Revisited, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Evolutionary Psychology: The Burdens of Proof, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Individuality and Adaptation Across Levels of Selection: How Shall We Name and Generalize the Unit of Darwinism? Stephen Jay Gould and Elisabeth A. Lloyd, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Elisabeth Lloyd's Views on the New Heritability Study of Female Orgasm, 2005 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Pluralism without Genic Causes? Elisabeth Lloyd, Matthew Dunn, Jennifer Cianciollo, and Costas Mannouris, 2005 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Why the Gene Will Not Return, 2005 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Lloyd's Reply to David Barash's Critique of The Case of the Female Orgasm, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Lloyd's Response to The Case of the Female Orgasm Critics, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Response to Puts and Dawood's 'The Evolution of Female Orgasm: Adaptation or Byproduct?' -- Been There, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - The Generational Cycle of State Spaces and Adequate Genetical Representation Elisabeth A. Lloyd, Richard C. Lewontin, and Marcus W. Feldman, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Female Sexual Arousal: Genital Anatomy and Orgasm in Intercourse Kim Wallen and Elisabeth A. Lloyd, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Zietsch and Santilla's Study is not Evidence Against the By-Product Theory of Female Orgasm Kim Wallen, P.Z. Meyers, and Elisabeth A. Lloyd, 2012 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Stephen J. Gould and Adaptation: San Marco 33 Years Later, 2013 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Adaptation and the Logic of Research Questions: How to Think Clearly About Evolutionary Causes, 2015 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Keywords in Evolutionary Biology Edited by Evelyn Fox Keller and Elisabeth Lloyd (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Successful Women are Discriminated Against Too Lisa Lloyd and Juliet Wittman (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - PhD Theses and Dissertations, 1989 - 2006; 5.
    - Burkhart, Brian (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Ekbia, Hamid R., 2003 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Forber, Patrick, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Hansen, Ben, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Haufe, Chris, 2006 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Jones, Martin Richard, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Kenen, Stephanie, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Lesser Blaker, Cynthia, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Lesser Blaker, Cynthia Cont'd., 1989 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Lovett, Laura (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Mladenović, Bojana, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Pojman, Paul, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Pojman, Paul, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Conferences, 1989 - 2016; VII.
  This series contains material derived from Lloyd's attendence at professional conferences. There can be programs, lists of talks, news bulletins and other materials.
  - Programs, 1983 - 2016; 1.
    - 7th Annual International Congress of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, Salzburg, Austria - Papers, Correspondence, Miscellaneous Documents, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Medical Miracles: Views from the Humanities Free Public Symposium at UCSD, May, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Foundations of Development and Evolution, Santa Fe Institute - Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 3)